O'NEIL KIMBI

Yaounde, Centre, Cameroon



oneilkimbi1@gmail.com



+237653916677



linkedin.com/in/oneil-kimbi

Summary

DevOps engineer/AWS solutions architect/full stack web developer with 5 years of experience and about hundreds of projects currently being consumed in the finance and IT sector. I emphasize on the need to understand the basics and advocate for full automation to save time and avoid unnecessary human errors. I can be so demanding at times, but the end product always brings joy to the room. I am willing to challenge myself in any project you deem complicated or needs extra efforts to go through.

From deadline pressure projects in the finance industry in Africa, to continuous development projects in the telecom industry in India and Europe, i can proudly say i am the next guy that will push your DevOps and general IT team to their extensive know-how. If the project is a challenging one, leave me a message here in LinkedIn or call me directly, in no time, the solution will be delivered.

Experience

Senior DevOps Engineer|AWS Solution architect

IDEAL INVESTMENT GROUP LTD

Aug 2020 - Present (3 years 1 month)

EC2 instance automation, deployment and monitoring with GIT, MAVEN, JENKINS, ANSIBLE AND TERAFORM. Performing all the stages in a CICD DevOps pipeline.

Python Developer

kimbi codes

Jan 2020 - Aug 2023 (3 years 8 months)

I develope small websites for businesses and personal websites using python anddjango i have done more than 10 websites for small businesses and individuals

Python Developer

Maki institute

Aug 2020 - Jun 2021 (11 months)

Develop and manage a school management software with Python using Django framwork

AWS/DevOps Engineer

IDEAL INVESTMENT GROUP LTD

Apr 2018 - Nov 2020 (2 years 8 months)

- Experienced in a waterfall, ITIL, SDLC, agile, and homegrown methodologies.
- Automated AWS and Azure infrastructure provisioning using Terraform and Cloud formation templates
- Performing configuration Automation using Chef & Ansible.

environment and introduced best practices for remediation

- Installation, Configuration and Management of RDBMS (MSSql, MySQL, Postgres,) & NoSQL (DynamoDB, MongoDB).
- · Creating S3 buckets and configuring Life Cycle Policies to drive cost optimization and High Availability.

- · Hands on Experience with EC2, ELB, AutoScaling, Lambdas, ELB, SNS, SWF, SQS etc
- Experience in configuring alarms and event actions using Cloud Watch & CloudTrail.
- Implemented a Continuous Delivery pipeline with GitHub, Jenkins, Docker and AWSAMI's, whenever a new GitHub branch gets started automatically and Jenkins our Continuous Integration server attempts to build a new Docker

container from it this Docker container has the AMI baked in and leverages Linux containers.

- Developed automation system using PowerShell, Python scripts and JSON templates to remediate the Azure services•
- Responsible for installing Jenkins master and slave nodes and also configure Jenkins builds for continuous integration and delivery.
- Collaborated with development support teams to setup a continuous delivery environment with the use of Docker.
- Developed microservice onboarding tools leveraging Python and Jenkins allowing for easy creation and maintenance of build jobs and kubernetes deploy and services.
- Involved in setting up builds using Chef as a configuration management tool and managed the configurations of more than 40 servers.
- · Automated webserver content deployments via shell scripts.
- Wrote Python scripts for pushing data from DynamoDB to MySQL Database.

Linux System Administrator

Hope Services

Jul 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 3 months)

- Responsible for installation, configuration, and administration of Red Hat Linux (RHEL), Solaris systems.
- Designed, supported, and maintained Oracle Real Application Clusters supporting business critical applications on HP Proliant BL465/BL685 & Integrity Itanium2 platforms on RHEL 4 & 5.
- Expanded the environment from 128 to over 280 systems over the course of 12 months.
- Setup and maintained NFS, NIS, and TCP/IP network, configured the systems for TCP/IP Networking with the existing LAN, setting up SSH and SCP features between SUN systems and other Red Hat/ UNIX hosts.
- Maintained network and data security, maintained security compliance policies on the OS for SOX and internal audits.
- Installed and configured VMware ESX server instances for virtual server setup and deployment. Responsible for

creating VMware virtual guests running Solaris, Linux, Windows.

- Integrated the Linux environment with Active Directory providing a Single Sign On (SSO) solution.
- Using rsyslog & mysql, deployed a custom syslog reporting solution for system alerts and notifications.
- Deployed Redhat Satellite Server with custom repositories to provide a stable management solution for the Linux environment.
- Experience with Jumpstart & Kickstart Installations on Solaris & Linux
- Installed, maintained and fine tuned the Apache-Tomcat server and Websphere Application Server in Linux Platform
- Created Bash/Korn shell scripts to monitor system resources and system maintenance.
- Wrote Perl and Python scripts to generate statistics and monitor processes.
- Deployed Active/Active MySQL clusters using Redhat Cluster Suite for supporting internal applications built on the LAMP stack.
- Automated system management tasks like user account creation, file system size monitoring, monitor system

resources and system maintenance using Shell, and Perl scripts.

 Worked with DBAs on installation of Oracle database, RDBMS database, restoration and log generation. Perform

Education

Keldin Institute Of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering Sep 2019 - May 2023 software engineer

coursera Coursera

DevOps Engineering , Computer Software Engineering Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

VTIAA

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2020 - 2022

Keldin institute of technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

Skills

Product Development • Leadership Development • Linux System Administration • VMWare ESXi • Oracle Database • PHP • Python (Programming Language) • Engineering